thank you
Monday night 8 pm and we're back with
your daily Market dose Corporate Central
where we get you the everyday pulse off
the corporate world and not just that
also taking note of all the market
fluctuations but first let's find out
what took place in the corporate world
today ICICI Lombard on Monday gained the
most since March 2020 on ICICI Bank
stake increase in early trade ICICI
Lombard shares were up nearly 12 percent
and this comes on the back of ICICI Bank
raising its stake in its uh listed
General Insurance joint venture with
Lombard to Beyond 50 making ICICI
Lombard officially a subsidiary the
board of directors approved an increase
in shareholding in the company in
multiple chances up to four four percent
out of which 2.5 percent will be bought
by ICICI Bank the insurer has said in a
statement to the exchanges on May 28 and
ICICI Bank had earlier on March 10th
informed the verses that RBI had granted
it an extension in the timeline for
diversing its shareholding in ICICI
Lombard to less than 30 percent of the
companies paid up Capital till September
9 2024 but now its board has given a
green flag to increase its stake in
ICICI Lombard by up to four percent in
multiple tranches as per the guidelines
of the Reserve Bank of India Banks can
own a shareholding of either less than
30 percent in insurance company or more
than 50 percent stake at close the
shares of icsl Lombard were trading at
1190 rupees up 8.9 percent
the holding company of wadia group The
Bombay Burma trading Corporation has
fully provided for its exposure to
bankrupt go first Airline and made a
provision of
1865.66 crore rupees for 2022-23 as
regards to its investments in go first
and other related Financial Obligations
excluding a share of the loss in go
first during the year the company owned
a 33 percent stake in go Airlines which
operates go first while the rest is
owned by unlisted holding companies of
the wadia group The Company also had a
debt exposure as of March this year and
has not made Provisions for exposure of
290 crore rupees as of March this year
which was said by bbtcl
in a relief for a Jala and Carl Rock
Consortium which has emerged as a
successful bidder to take over Jet
Airways the ncl80 on 26 May granted it
more time to make payments to the State
Bank of India the apply tribunal said
that the nclt had approved the
consortium's resolution plan in January
but the matter on appeal for stay Was
Heard by it in March which was turned
down hence it would be proper that jkc
gets an exclusion from November 16 2022
till March 3rd 2023 from complying with
payment obligation towards SBI the
enclat has also pulled up SBI for
threatening to invoke Bank guarantees
instead of cooperating with jkc and
implementing the resolution plan it
noted that performance Bank guarantee
can be invoked by lenders but only when
successful resolution applicant has
failed to implement the plan
modi's investor service on Friday has
said that it has upgraded its rating
outlook on Tata Motors to positive from
stable the agency expects the
Improvement in the Indian automakers
credit profile to sustain for the next
12 to 18 months according to a statement
on Friday it also forecasts sustained
Improvement in all three automotive
automotive operations commercial vehicle
passenger vehicle and a Jaguar Land
Rover Automotive in terms of a ratings
action it affirmed its B1 corporate
family rating and B1 senior unsecured
ratings for atata Motors Modis said that
it would upgrade the ratings if Tata
Motors delivers a slightly longer track
record of consistent Improvement in its
credit profile
Sun pharmaceutical Industries has said
that it has proposed to fully acquire
israel-based Taro pharmaceutical
Industries through a reverse triangular
merger the mumbai-based drug major said
that it has issued a letter to the Tarot
Board with a proposal containing a
non-binding indication of interest to
acquire all of the outstanding ordinary
shares for a purchase price of 38
dollars per ordinary share in cash Sun
Pharma currently owns a 78.48 stake in
Taro the purchase price represents a
premium of 31.2 percent over taro's
closing price on May 25th 2023 which was
a 41.5 percent premium over taro's
average closing price in the last 60
days and a compelling liquidity
opportunity for taro's shareholders
under the indicative proposal post the
acquisition Taro will become a wholly
owned subsidy of sun Pharma and will be
delisted from NYSE
U.S based asset management firm Baron
Capital group has reduced food and
grocery delivery companies twiggy's
valuation by another 10 percent yet
again to 6.38 billion dollars as of
March 31st 2023 the company has
estimated the fair value of its take in
the company at about
45.76 million dollars according to the
investors filings on the Securities and
Exchange Commission this development
comes uh weeks after it was reported
that Baron Capital marked down the
bengaluru-based companies valuation by
34 to 7.1 billion dollars as of December
2022. Baron Capital participated in an
investment round in January last year
when swiggy had raised 700 million
dollars the fundraise was led by U.S
based investment firm Invesco and saw
the participation of Baron Capital so
meru Venture iifl among others apart
from Baron U.S based Invesco also had
slashed swiggy's valuation to about 5.5
billion dollars as but it's recent
filings despite the markdown swiggy on
May 18th announced that it has turned
profitable
as per a business standard report
e-commerce player misho backed by
Marquee investors like SoftBank group
and meta platforms we'll look at the IPO
only in 2025 and until then its focus is
to generate profits after tax and not
just be editor that is earnings before
interest taxes depreciation and
amortization positive in a clear shift
of strategy the company which has
reduced its cash Burn by 85 percent is
now looking to trim its annual revenue
growth Target to 40 from the 100 plus
percent earlier sources have however
confirmed in the report that even at
this level of growth was Far higher than
that of e-commerce most e-commerce
companies in FY 22 misho saw its
revenues the jump 4.5 times year on year
two while its losses Rose even more
steeply by 7.5 times the startup makes
around 10 percent margins on its
transactions so whose average ticket
size is 350 rupees
BPA formerly known as bearing private
Equity Asia has emerged as the front
runner to acquire a majority stake in
credila Financial Services Limited the
education loan unit of HDFC limited for
as much as 1.5 billion dollars that is
12 000 crore rupees the Asian buyout
fund will likely pip rival bidders
including Blackstone Carlisle ta
Associates and CVC Capital to clinch the
deal as per reports the deal is in the
final stages and is likely to be
announced in June ahead of the mega
merger between HDFC and HDFC Bank
earlier this month various media reports
made rounds saying that Blackstone
Warburg pinkers and Sovereign wealth
funds such as Abu Dhabi investment
Authority and Singapore's GIC had
expressed interest in acquiring a stake
in credila
well that was all about corporates now
let's take a look at those market stocks
that were in the spotlight today and
also analyze the reason behind it
first up after disappointing fourth
quarter results on gc's talk on Monday
saw the biggest fall in six months after
November 21st 2022. it touched an
intraday low of 156.50 rupees before
closing at 159 rupees in fact quarter
one quarter the company has turned from
profit to loss in quarter four during
the quarter the company has posted a
loss of 247.7 crore rupees as against a
profit of 11
044.8 crore rupees this is because the
company has registered a one-time loss
of nine thousand two thirty five crore
rupees in the company has in fact made a
provisioning of 12 107 crore rupees for
the dispute related to service and GST
as well as interest payment on royalty
payment this matter is related to
royalty payment from April 1st 2016 to
March 31st 2023 and although the company
will continue the legal battle on this
matter meanwhile the income in quarter
four decreased by 5.9 percent from
thirty eight thousand five eighty three
point three crore Rupees to 20 six
thousand two ninety two point six crore
rupees operating profit quarter on
quarter declined by 19.9 percent to
sixteen thousand three forty crore
rupees from 20
411.1 crore rupees and operating margins
to erode it operating margin declined to
45 percent from 52.9 percent in quarter
three
and there is also news that the company
has announced to start gas production
from Krishna godavari Basin from June
15th and for this the company has also
invited bids and has demanded 12 per
unit
the city Union Bank share fell up to 10
percent after the fourth quarter results
even though the bank's results have been
good the stock touched a low of 125.65
rupees during the day nii that is a net
interest income grew by 2.7 percent year
on Year from 500.7 rupees uh 500.7 crore
Rupees to
514.2 crore rupees profit grew by just
4.3 percent from 209 crore Rupees to 218
crore rupees because provisioning has
come down by seven percent year on year
gross npas of the bank have come down
from 4.62 percent to 4.37 on a quarterly
basis net npas have come down from 2.67
to 2.36 percent but the results have
been less than the market estimates due
to which the stock has seen a decline
the second disappointment has been on
the front of Nims that is net interest
margin the banks are quarter on quarter
Nims came down from 3.88 to 3.65 percent
the third reason is that according to
Brokers the results are weak and the
road ahead is challenging ICICI
Securities has reduced rating from ad to
hold with a target of 140 rupees
similarly Nirmal bang has also
downgraded a rating to accumulate and
Target is at 151 rupees Alara Capital
has also maintained accumulate rating
with a target of 145 rupees
shares of gmr airports plunged more than
11 percent on Monday and the stock
touched an entered a low of 40 rupees
during the day which is the reason for
the very disappointing quarter four
results in fact in quarter four the
company's year-on-year losses have
increased the company has incurred a
loss of 441.5 crore rupees in the fourth
quarter and the company's loss in the
same period last year was 141.3 crore
rupees although the company's income
during this period has increased by 47.6
percent from
1283.6 crore rupees two thousand eight
ninety four point six crore rupees the
biggest problem for the company is the
performance at the operating level the
operating profit of the company has
decreased by 51.5 percent from 534 crore
Rupees to 259 crore rupees and the
margin has also registered a huge
decline working margins have declined
from 41.6 percent year on year to just
13.7 percent in quarter four
stocks of balakrishna Industries gained
almost 26 percent in the last two months
and this was also seen because the
results are to be expected to be good as
seen in other companies of the sector on
the contrary to the rest of the
companies in the sector there has been a
decline in all parameters companies
income in quarter four has decreased by
2.4 percent from 2374 crore Rupees to 2
318 crore rupees working profit has
decreased by six percent from a 500
crore Rupees to 471 crore rupees the
operating margin declined from 21 to
20.3 percent and the profit decreased by
32 percent from 374 crore Rupees to 256
crore rupees while other companies in
the sector have seen at least 100 growth
in profits management commentary has
also been a week according to management
Channel inventory issues continue which
has resulted in decline in sales the
management expects Channel inventory
issues to be resolved by June July but
the market is assuming that the results
of the first quarter of y24 may also
remain Under Pressure this is very
important for the company because about
50 percent of the company's income comes
from abroad
that's all tonight on Corporate Central
but before we leave leaving you with
some important corporate events and
triggers which have the potential to
make big Market impacts first up results
on May 29th most awaited results of
IRCTC were released whose impact were
felt in the market and a globally U.S
and UK markets have remained closed on
May 30th results of Apollo hospitals
adani ports to be released and also
board meeting on a torrent Pharma
results is on May 30th where along with
the results board will consider raising
funds and also the board meeting on
Balmer Lorry results on May 30th wherein
buy back or bonus shares will also be
decided by the board
and X date of a dividend of ITC vedanta
also falls on May 30th
and globally U.S March house price index
figures to be released on May 30th Also
may consumer confidence figures of us
and also the Europe to be released on
May 30th
well with that it's a wrap on a
Corporate Central tonight but you can
catch all the other detailed updates on
a corporate world on money9's website
www.money9.com that's all from me take
care and see you tomorrow
thank you
[Music]